A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, The Fund for the Advancement of Education (TFAE) files FA740
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, The Fund for the Advancement of Education (TFAE) files
1939-1976
Rockefeller Archive Center
Fund for the Advancement of Education (U.S.)
Ford Foundation
FA740
254.4 Cubic Feet 212 boxes.
212 record storage cartons.
Biographical/Historical note
The Fund for the Advancement of Education (TFAE) was established in 1951 to support new and experimental programs at all levels of formal education. The five areas to which TFAE focused its resources were: the equalization of educational opportunity; improvements in curricula; clarification of the functions of educational institutions; improvement of educational management and financing; and the improvement of teaching. TFAE operated for over a decade. It ceased funding new projects in the late 1960s.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Conditions Governing Access note
Records more than 10 years old are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Completion of a use agreement is required prior to providing scholarly access. See RAC Head of Reference (or applicable designee) for details.
Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Arrangement
The TFAE files are arranged in 5 series:
I. Board of Directors and Administrative Files. II. Grant Awardees - Educational Institutions. III. Grant Awardees - Multi-Institutional (not Fund Administered). IV. Conferences. V. Publications.
Scope and Contents
Primarily consists of: Administrative files, Grant files, correspondence and reports, Board of Directors records, financial records, and documentation of conferences and publications.
- Board of Directors and Administrative Files, 1939-1972; I; 33.6 Cubic Feet 28 boxes.
  Arrangement note
  The Board of Directors and Administrative Files series is comprised of nine sub-series: Board of Directors Files; G.H. Griffith and Clarence Faust Correspondence Files; Officers and Staff Files; Personnel and Administrative Files; Consultants Files; General Correspondence Files; Financial Files; Organization Files; and Reference Clippings Files.
  - Board of Directors Files, 1951-1972; 1; 7.2 Cubic Feet 6 boxes.; 6 boxes
    Scope and Contents note
    The Board of Directors sub-series contains meeting minutes and agenda, and files on individual board members, officers and staff. The minutes and by-laws are in bound volumes and dated 1951-1964.
    - Board Minutes, 1971 - 1972 (Box 1 (49534))
    - Index of Education Programs, 1966 - 1972 (Box 1 (49534))
    - Fiscal Report, 1967 (Box 1 (49534))
    - Board Meeting, 1967 December 11 (Box 1 (49534))
    - Elections, By-Laws, Resolutions, 1967 (Box 1 (49534))
    - Board Meeting, 1967 July 20 (Box 1 (49534))
    - Publicity and Policy - Reece Committee, 1954 (Box 1 (49534))
    - Board Meeting, 1967 April (Box 1 (49534))
    - Board Meeting, 1967 January (Box 1 (49534))
    - Application for Grants, 1953 - 1954 (Box 1 (49534))
    - List of Active Grants, 1967 (Box 1 (49534))
    - Board Minutes, 1964 - 1966 (Box 1 (49534))
    - Board Minutes, 1964 - 1966 (Box 1 (49534))
    - Board Minutes, 1961 - 1963 (Box 1 (49534))
    - Board Minutes, 1961 - 1963 (Box 1 (49534))
    - Board Minutes, 1959 - 1960 (Box 1 (49534))
    - Board Minutes, 1957 - 1958 (Box 1 (49534))
    - Board Minutes, 1955 - 1956 (Box 1 (49534))
    - Board Minutes, 1953 - 1954 (Box 1 (49534))
    - Board Minutes, 1951 - 1952 (Box 1 (49534))
    - Board of Directors - TFAE Sponsored Projects, 1951-1952 (Box 1 (49534))
    - Reports, 1951 (Box 1 (49534))
    - Directors: M&R: Board Meeting, June 1951 (Box 1 (49534))
    - The Fund for the Advancement of Education - Board Minutes, 1951 - 1952 (Box 1 (49534))
    - The Fund for the Advancement of Education - Board Minutes, 1954 - 1957 (Box 1 (49534))
    - The Fund for the Advancement of Education - Board Minutes, 1961 - 1963 (Box 2 (49535))
    - The Fund for the Advancement of Education - Board Minutes - Executive Committee, 1958 - 1963 (Box 2 (49535))
    - The Fund for the Advancement of Education - Board Minutes, 1957 - 1960 (Box 2 (49535))
    - The Fund for the Advancement of Education - Board Minutes, 1952 - 1954 (Box 2 (49535))
    - The Fund for the Advancement of Education - Board Minutes, 1951 - 1957 (Box 2 (49535))
    - The Fund for the Advancement of Education - Board Minutes, 1964 - 1970 (Box 2 (49535))
    - Meeting Agenda - January 24, 1966 (Box 3 (49536))
    - Meeting Agenda - October 24, 1966 (Box 3 (49536))
    - Meeting Agenda - April 25, 1966 (Box 3 (49536))
    - Meeting Agenda - October 25, 1965 (Box 3 (49536))
    - Meeting Agenda - April 26, 1965 (Box 3 (49536))
    - Meeting Agenda - January 11, 1965 (Box 3 (49536))
    - Meeting Agenda - October 26, 1964 (Box 3 (49536))
    - Meeting Agenda - April 27, 1964 (Box 3 (49536))
    - Meeting Agenda - January 27, 1964 (Box 3 (49536))
    - Meeting Agenda - October 28, 1963 (Box 3 (49536))
    - Meeting Agenda - April 22, 1963 (Box 3 (49536))
    - Meeting Agenda - January 28, 1963 (Box 3 (49536))
    - Meeting Agenda - October 22, 1962 (Box 3 (49536))
    - Meeting Agenda - April 23, 1962 (Box 3 (49536))
    - Meeting Agenda - January 22, 1962 (Box 3 (49536))
    - Meeting Agenda - October 23, 1961 (Box 3 (49536))
    - Meeting Agenda - April 24, 1961 (Box 3 (49536))
    - Meeting Agenda - January 23, 1961 (Box 3 (49536))
    - Meeting Agenda - October 24, 1960 (Box 3 (49536))
    - Meeting Agenda - April 19, 1960 (Box 3 (49536))
    - Meeting Agenda - January 19, 1960 (Box 3 (49536))
    - Meeting Agenda - October 20, 1959 (Box 3 (49536))
    - Meeting Agenda - April 27, 1959 (Box 3 (49536))
    - Meeting Agenda - January 26, 1959 (Box 3 (49536))
    - Meeting Agenda - October 20, 1958 (Box 3 (49536))
    - Meeting Agenda - May 26, 1958 (Box 3 (49536))
    - Meeting Agenda - January 14, 1958 (Box 3 (49536))
    - Board Meeting, 1963 October 28 (Box 4 (49537))
    - Board Meeting, 1960 January 19 (Box 4 (49537))
    - Board Meeting, 1959 January 26 (Box 4 (49537))
    - Correspondence, 1955 - 1957 (Box 4 (49537))
    - Conference - July 10, 1958 (Box 4 (49537))
    - Fellowship Programs, 1953 (Box 4 (49537))
    - Free University of Berlin, 1951 - 1953 (Box 4 (49537))
    - Freedom Seminar, 1951 (Box 4 (49537))
    - General, 1951 - 1957 (Box 4 (49537))
    - Grants, 1951 - 1952 (Box 4 (49537))
    - Individual Fellowships, 1953 (Box 4 (49537))
    - National Merit Scholarship Fund, 1952 - 1955 (Box 4 (49537))
    - Peace Seminar, 1951 (Box 4 (49537))
    - Policy Information, 1952 - 1955 (Box 4 (49537))
    - Resources Program, 1952 - 1953 (Box 4 (49537))
    - Abrams, Frank W., 1952 - 1960 (Box 4 (49537))
    - Adams, Frederick B., Jr., 1958 - 1959 (Box 4 (49537))
    - Berelson, Bernard, 1953 - 1956 (Box 4 (49537))
    - Bingham, Barry, 1952 - 1955 (Box 4 (49537))
    - Browne, Dyke, 1953 - 1955 (Box 4 (49537))
    - Bunche, Ralph, 1950 - 1958 (Box 4 (49537))
    - Carroll, Thomas H., 1955 - 1960 (Box 4 (49537))
    - Dickey, Charles D., 1958 (Box 4 (49537))
    - Douglas, James H., 1954 - 1963 (Box 4 (49537))
    - Ensminger, Douglas, 1953 - 1956 (Box 4 (49537))
    - Fletcher, Scott C., 1951 - 1960 (Box 4 (49537))
    - Ford, Henry II, 1952 - 1955 (Box 4 (49537))
    - Gaither, Rowan, 1953 - 1960 (Box 4 (49537))
    - Gifford, Walter S., 1954 (Box 4 (49537))
    - Gladieux, Bernard L., 1954 (Box 4 (49537))
    - Heald, Henry, 1956 - 1957 (Box 4 (49537))
    - Heckscher, Maurice, 1958 - 1963 (Box 4 (49537))
    - Hoffman, Paul, 1951 - 1955 (Box 4 (49537))
    - Horton, Mildred, 1951 - 1963 (Box 4 (49537))
    - Houghton, Arthur A., 1956 - 1960 (Box 4 (49537))
    - Katz, Milton, 1953 - 1955 (Box 4 (49537))
    - Larson, Roy, 1952 - 1960 (Box 4 (49537))
    - Lippman, Walter, 1954 (Box 4 (49537))
    - McGill, Ralph, 1955 - 1960 (Box 4 (49537))
    - McPeak, William, 1952 - 1959 (Box 4 (49537))
    - Mellon, Paul, 1952 - 1955 (Box 4 (49537))
    - Paepcke, Walter Paul, 1952 - 1960 (Box 4 (49537))
    - Reed, Philip D., 1953 (Box 4 (49537))
    - Roberts, Owen J., 1953 - 1955 (Box 4 (49537))
    - Young, James Webb, 1954 (Box 4 (49537))
    - Board Meeting - April 18, 1957 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Board Meeting - March 13, 1957 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Board Meeting - January 28, 1957 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Board Meeting - September 20, 1956 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Board Meeting - July 1956 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Board Meeting - April 1956 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Board Meeting - Faust Report - March 1956 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Board Meeting - January 30, 1956 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Board Meeting - October 1955 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Board Meeting - Activity Report - June to September 1955 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Executive Committee Meeting - June 20, 1955 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Board Meeting - Activity Report - April to June 1955 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Executive Committee Meeting - April 13 to 14, 1955 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Board Meeting - April 1955 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Board Meeting - Activity Report - January to March 1955 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Board Meeting - Activity Report - December to February 1954 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Executive Committee Meeting - November 4, 1954 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Board Meeting - September 1954 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Executive Committee Meeting - July 1954 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Board Meeting - June 1954 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Board Meeting - Activity Report June 1954 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Board Meeting - April 1954 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Board Meeting - Activity Report - April 1954 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Board Meeting - January 1954 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Board Meeting - December 1953 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Board Meeting - October 1953 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Board Meeting - Activity Report - October to December 1953 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Board Meeting - Activity Report September to October 1953 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Board Meeting - Activity Report - June to September 1953 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Board Meeting - June 1953 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Executive Committee - June 1953 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Board Meeting - April 1953 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Board Meeting - Activity Report - March to April 1953 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Board Meeting - March 1953 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Board Meeting - Activity Report - January 1953 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Board Meeting - January 1953 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Board Meeting - Activity Report - 1952 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Board Meeting - Activity Reports - Board, December 1952 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Board Meeting - October 1952 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Board Meeting - June 1952 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Board Meeting - April 1952 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Committee on Annual Awards - 1952 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Board Meeting - Abrams report to Hoffman - January 1952 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Board Meeting - January 1952 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Board Meeting - Activity Report - December 1951 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Board Meeting - October 1951 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Executive Committee Meeting - December 1952 (Box 5 (49538))
    - Board of Directors Meeting October 7, 1957 (Box 6 (49539))
    - Board of Directors Meeting April 29, 1957 (Box 6 (49539))
    - Board of Directors Meeting January 28, 1957 (Box 6 (49539))
    - Board of Directors Meeting September 24, 1956 (Box 6 (49539))
    - Board of Directors Meeting April 30, 1956 (Box 6 (49539))
    - Board of Directors Meeting January 30, 1956 (Box 6 (49539))
    - Board of Directors Meeting October 31, 1955 (Box 6 (49539))
    - Board of Directors Meeting April 18, 1955 (Box 6 (49539))
    - Board of Directors Meeting January 31, 1955 (Box 6 (49539))
    - Board of Directors Meeting September 27, 1954 (Box 6 (49539))
    - Board of Directors Meeting June 14, 1954 (Box 6 (49539))
    - Board of Directors Meeting April 15, 1954 (Box 6 (49539))
    - Board of Directors Meeting January 23, 1954 (Box 6 (49539))
    - Board of Directors Meeting - November 24, 1953 (Box 6 (49539))
    - Board of Directors Meeting October 19, 1953 (Box 6 (49539))
    - Board of Directors Meeting - June 16, 1953 (Box 6 (49539))
    - Board of Directors Meeting - April 6, 1953 (Box 6 (49539))
    - Board of Directors Meeting - April 6, 1953 (Box 6 (49539))
    - Board of Directors Meeting - January 26, 1953 (Box 6 (49539))
    - Board of Directors Meeting - October 20, 1952 (Box 6 (49539))
    - Board of Directors Meeting - October 17, 1952 (Box 6 (49539))
    - Board of Directors Meeting - June 23, 1952 (Box 6 (49539))
    - Board of Directors Meeting - April 10, 1952 (Box 6 (49539))
    - Board of Directors Meeting - January 18, 1952 (Box 6 (49539))
    - Board of Directors Meeting - October 25, 1951 (Box 6 (49539))
    - Board of Directors Meeting - April 1951 to May 1952, 1951 - 1952 (Box 6 (49539))
  - Director Correspondence Files - G.H. Griffith and Clarence Faust, 1951-1972; 2; 6 Cubic Feet 5 boxes.; 5 boxes
    G.H. Griffith and Clarence Faust Correspondence Files sub-series includes the correspondence as directed to the Board of Directors and concerns TFAE operations and grants.
    - Clarence Faust Correspondence Files - Abrams, Frank, 1953 - 1963 (Box 1 (49540))
    - Clarence Faust Correspondence Files - Bingham, Barry, 1951 - 1965 (Box 1 (49540))
    - Clarence Faust Correspondence Files - Bunche, Ralph, 1951 - 1960 (Box 1 (49540))
    - Clarence Faust Correspondence Files - Case, Everett Mrs., 1965 (Box 1 (49540))
    - Clarence Faust Correspondence Files - Charyk, Joseph V., 1965 (Box 1 (49540))
    - Clarence Faust Correspondence Files - Dickey, Charles, 1951 - 1963 (Box 1 (49540))
    - Clarence Faust Correspondence Files - Douglas, James H. Jr., 1951 - 1964 (Box 1 (49540))
    - Clarence Faust Correspondence Files - Fletcher, C. Scott, 1951 - 1955 (Box 1 (49540))
    - Clarence Faust Correspondence Files - Gifford, Walter S. (Box 1 (49540))
    - Clarence Faust Correspondence Files - Heckscher, Maurice, 1958 - 1965 (Box 1 (49540))
    - Clarence Faust Correspondence Files - Horton, Mrs. Mildred McAfee, 1951 - 1966 (Box 1 (49540))
    - Clarence Faust Correspondence Files - Howe, Arthur Jr., 1965 (Box 1 (49540))
    - Clarence Faust Correspondence Files - Lippmann, Walter, 1953 - 1965 (Box 1 (49540))
    - Clarence Faust Correspondence Files - Larsen, Roy E., 1951 - 1964 (Box 1 (49540))
    - Clarence Faust Correspondence Files - McGill, Ralph E., 1954 - 1965 (Box 1 (49540))
    - Clarence Faust Correspondence Files - Mellon, Paul, 1951 - 1957 (Box 1 (49540))
    - Clarence Faust Correspondence Files - Reed, Philip D., 1952 - 1953 (Box 1 (49540))
    - Clarence Faust Correspondence Files - Roberts, Justice Owen J., 1951 - 1956 (Box 1 (49540))
    - Clarence Faust Correspondence Files - Young, James, 1951 - 1964 (Box 1 (49540))
    - G.H. Griffths Correspondence Files - Bowles, Frank, 1965 - 1966 (Box 1 (49540))
    - G.H. Griffths Correspondence Files - Bundy, McGeorge, 1966 - 1967 (Box 1 (49540))
    - G.H. Griffths Correspondence Files - Cleveland, Harlan, 1959 - 1966 (Box 1 (49540))
    - G.H. Grifftihs Correspondence - Building Program, 1964 - 1966 (Box 1 (49540))
    - G.H. Griffths Correspondence Files - Clippings, 1965 - 1966 (Box 1 (49540))
    - G.H. Griffths Correspondence Files - Docket Items, 1964 - 1967 (Box 1 (49540))
    - G.H. Griffths Correspondence Files - Education Program, 1965 - 1966 (Box 1 (49540))
    - G.H. Griffths Correspondence Files - Education and Research Division, 1968 (Box 1 (49540))
    - G.H. Griffths Correspondence Files - Financial, 1951 - 1967 (Box 1 (49540))
    - G.H. Griffths Correspondence Files - Financial - Public Education, 1967 (Box 1 (49540))
    - G.H. Griffths Correspondence Files - Fletcher, Scott, 1961 - 1966 (Box 1 (49540))
    - G.H. Griffths Correspondence Files - Foundation Forum Planning Committee, 1967 (Box 1 (49540))
    - G.H. Griffths Correspondence Files - Fund - Administrative, 1952 - 1968 (Box 1 (49540))
    - G.H. Griffths Correspondence Files - Fund - By Laws, 1967 (Box 1 (49540))
    - G.H. Griffths Correspondence Files - Fund - Insurance, 1967 (Box 1 (49540))
    - G.H. Griffths Correspondence Files - Fund - Letters to and from Board, 1967 (Box 1 (49540))
    - G.H. Griffths Correspondence Files - Fund - Legal, 1951 - 1956 (Box 1 (49540))
    - G.H. Griffths Correspondence Files - Fund - Memos, 1967 (Box 1 (49540))
    - G.H. Griffths Correspondence Files - Fund - Tax Rulings, 1952 - 1958 (Box 1 (49540))
    - G.H. Griffths Correspondence Files - Great Cities, 1959 (Box 1 (49540))
    - G.H. Griffths Correspondence Files - Memos, 1961 - 1964 (Box 1 (49540))
    - G.H. Griffths Correspondence Files - Pending Approvals, 1965 - 1967 (Box 1 (49540))
    - G.H. Griffths Correspondence Files - Negro Education, 1963 - 1966 (Box 1 (49540))
    - Chronological Copies - April to June 1967 (Box 2 (49541))
    - Chronological Copies - January to March 1967 (Box 2 (49541))
    - Chronological Copies - January to March 1966 (Box 2 (49541))
    - Chronological Copies - April to June 1966 (Box 2 (49541))
    - Chronological Copies - October to December 1966 (Box 2 (49541))
    - Chronological Copies - July to December 1966 (Box 2 (49541))
    - Chronological Copies - October to December 1965 (Box 2 (49541))
    - Chronological Copies - A through K - July to September 1965 (Box 2 (49541))
    - Chronological Copies - L through Z - January to June 1965 (Box 2 (49541))
    - Chronological Copies - October 1964 (Box 2 (49541))
    - Chronological Copies - July to September 1964 (Box 2 (49541))
    - Chronological Copies - April to June 1964 (Box 2 (49541))
    - Chronological Copies - January to March 1964 (Box 2 (49541))
    - Chronological Copies - October to December 1963 (Box 2 (49541))
    - Chronological Copies - July to September 1963 (Box 2 (49541))
    - Chronological Copies - April to June 1963 (Box 2 (49541))
    - Chronological Copies - January to March 1963 (Box 2 (49541))
    - Chronological Copies - December 1962 (Box 2 (49541))
    - Chronological Copies - July to September 1962 (Box 2 (49541))
    - Chronological Copies - April to June 1962 (Box 2 (49541))
    - Chronological Copies - January to March 1962 (Box 2 (49541))
    - Chronological Copies - June to July 1961 (Box 2 (49541))
    - Chronological Copies - January to May 30, 1961 (Box 2 (49541))
    - Chronological Copies - September to July 1960 (Box 2 (49541))
    - Chronological Copies - October to December 1960 (Box 2 (49541))
    - Chronological Copies - January to March 1960 (Box 2 (49541))
    - Chronological Copies - April to June 1960 (Box 2 (49541))
    - Chronological Copies - October to December 1961 (Box 2 (49541))
    - Chronological File - July 1971 to January 1972, 1971 - 1972 (Box 3 (49542))
    - Chronological File - January to June 1971 (Box 3 (49542))
    - Chronological File - January to June 1970 (Box 3 (49542))
    - Chronological File - July to December 1969 (Box 3 (49542))
    - Chronological File - January to June 1969 (Box 3 (49542))
    - Chronological File - April to June 1968 (Box 3 (49542))
    - Chronological File - May to June 1968 (Box 3 (49542))
    - Chronological File - September to December 1968 (Box 3 (49542))
    - Chronological File - March to May 1968 (Box 3 (49542))
    - Chronological File - June to July 1968 (Box 3 (49542))
    - Pending - with Dunbar of the Field Foundation - 1967 to 1968, 1967 - 1968 (Box 3 (49542))
    - Chronological File - October to December 1967 (Box 3 (49542))
    - Chronological File - July to Septemebr 1967 (Box 3 (49542))
    - Press Release - Close Out of TFAE - April 1967 (Box 3 (49542))
    - University Council - 1962 to 1965, 1962 - 1965 (Box 3 (49542))
    - Staff Papers - 1965 to 1966, 1965 - 1966 (Box 3 (49542))
    - Pending - University of South Florida - 1966 (Box 3 (49542))
    - Pending - Adult Education Program in the South - 1966 to 1967, 1966 - 1967 (Box 3 (49542))
    - G.H. Griffiths Correspondence Files - Board Minutes, 1972 (Box 4 (49543))
    - G.H. Griffiths Correspondence Files - Fund for Adult Education, 1970 (Box 4 (49543))
    - G.H. Griffiths Correspondence Files - Fund for Adult Education, 1969 (Box 4 (49543))
    - G.H. Griffiths Correspondence Files - Fund for Adult Education, 1968 (Box 4 (49543))
    - G.H. Griffiths Correspondence Files - America's University of - Report, 1967 (Box 4 (49543))
    - G.H. Griffiths Correspondence Files - Board Minutes, 1967 (Box 4 (49543))
    - G.H. Griffiths Correspondence Files - Brothers of Saint Pius X Proposal, 1967 (Box 4 (49543))
    - G.H. Griffiths Correspondence Files - Tennessee, University of, 1967 (Box 4 (49543))
    - G.H. Griffiths Correspondence Files - Teachers College - Columbia University, 1965 - 1967 (Box 4 (49543))
    - G.H. Griffiths Correspondence Files - Fund for Adult Education, 1966 - 1967 (Box 4 (49543))
    - G.H. Griffiths Correspondence Files - Fund for Adult Education, 1960 - 1966 (Box 4 (49543))
    - G.H. Griffiths Correspondence Files - Fund for Adult Education, 1965 (Box 4 (49543))
    - G.H. Griffiths Correspondence Files - Fund for Adult Education - Financial, 1960 - 1965 (Box 4 (49543))
    - G.H. Griffiths Correspondence Files - Grant Information, 1958 - 1965 (Box 4 (49543))
    - G.H. Griffiths Correspondence Files - Grant Information, 1959 - 1964 (Box 4 (49543))
    - G.H. Griffiths Correspondence Files - Fund for Adult Education - Board Meeting, 1964 (Box 4 (49543))
    - G.H. Griffiths Correspondence Files - Fund for Adult Education - Board Meeting, 1963 (Box 4 (49543))
    - G.H. Griffiths Correspondence Files - Fund for Adult Education - Board Meeting, 1962 (Box 4 (49543))
    - G.H. Griffiths Correspondence Files - Board Minutes, 1961 - 1962 (Box 4 (49543))
    - G.H. Griffiths Correspondence Files - Fund for Adult Education - Board Meeting, 1961 (Box 4 (49543))
    - G.H. Griffiths Correspondence Files - Fund for Adult Education - Board Meeting, 1961 (Box 4 (49543))
    - G.H. Griffiths Correspondence Files - Board Meeting, 1967 (Box 5 (49544))
    - G.H. Griffiths Correspondence Files - Board Meeting, 1966 (Box 5 (49544))
    - G.H. Griffiths Correspondence Files - Active Grants, 1966 (Box 5 (49544))
    - G.H. Griffiths Correspondence Files - Board Meeting, 1965 (Box 5 (49544))
    - G.H. Griffiths Correspondence Files - Books for Disadvantaged, 1966 (Box 5 (49544))
    - G.H. Griffiths Correspondence Files - Exploratory Committee on Assessing Progress of Education, 1966 (Box 5 (49544))
    - G.H. Griffiths Correspondence Files - College Financial Aid Information for Negro High School Students, 1966 (Box 5 (49544))
    - G.H. Griffiths Correspondence Files - Documentation of Civil Rights Movement, 1966 (Box 5 (49544))
    - G.H. Griffiths Correspondence Files - Specialized Training for Teachers of Culturally Deprived Children, 1966 (Box 5 (49544))
    - G.H. Griffiths Correspondence Files - Information Services on Computers in American Education, 1966 (Box 5 (49544))
    - G.H. Griffiths Correspondence Files - Travel and Study for Teachers and Administration, 1966 (Box 5 (49544))
    - G.H. Griffiths Correspondence Files - Early Childhood Education, 1965 (Box 5 (49544))
    - G.H. Griffiths Correspondence Files - Faculty Leave Programs, 1965 (Box 5 (49544))